Andrew (Howon) Kim

Computer Vision Manager

Austintown, OH howonkim@berkeley.edu + 1 (724) 682-0714

I have **diverse experience**, ranging from **building a startup** from its inception to scaling it up and **working in prominent companies**. In my first six months at LG and GM, I greatly achieved the **first prize in a worldwide data analysis competition** and also received Golden Awards for my contributions to smart factory initiatives. My commitment to excellence and innovation drives my success in delivering impactful results.

Education

University of California, Berkeley, CA

2022

Graduated as Data Science: Applied Mathematics and Modeling with Computer Science and Data Science cores.

Experience

Ultium Cells | Computer Vision Inspection Manager (L4B)

10/2024 - Present

Company of General Motors and LG Energy Solution | Lordstown, OH

- Led the optimization of the in-line inspection system, enhancing defect detection accuracy and process reliability resulting in a production yield increase from 96% to 98%.
- Developed C#/WinUI 3 app for real-time QC; used SQL indexing and queries to speed up historical defect lookup.
- Improved rule-based detection algorithm with deep learning models built from scratch (PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras), boosting accuracy by 20%+.

Ultium Cells | Computer Vision Engineer

04/2023 - 10/2024

Company of General Motors and LG Energy Solution | Lordstown, OH

- Awarded 1st Prize in a global data analysis competition, showcasing advanced skills in Python and data analysis.
- Experienced with machine learning frameworks and proficient in using various vector databases.
- Strong understanding of advanced manufacturing systems, including PLC, SPC, and MES.
- Developed **statistical**, **deep learning algorithms** for defect detection using terabytes of manufacturing data.

ReviewMe | ML Model Development and iOS Programming

09/2020 - 12/2021

eBook Review Platform Startup | Seoul, Korea

- Analyzed brain waves and facial components to develop a deep learning model that evaluates concentration levels, enhancing review systems through facial analysis.
- Proficient in Swift, SwiftUI, MLKit, ARKit, and Vision Framework for building advanced iOS applications.
- Contribute a patent for a Kindle-like review system and recipient of government AI funding.

Samsung Electronics | ML Model Development and Android Programming (Internship)

06/2020 - 08/2020

Software Engineer Internship at Android Framework Department | Suwon, Korea

- Researched a machine learning project for automatic sorting of notifications based on situational importance.
- Analyzed and optimized Samsung frameworks using Kotlin and Java to improve performance and functionality.
- Skilled in Git, documentation, and agile development practices; led weekly sprint planning sessions for intern team.

AltoyGames | Unity3D Game Engineer and Co-Founder

01/2020 - 06/2020

Game Studio Startup | Suwon, Korea

• Game development in Unity 3D and C#. Developed core components and algorithms from 2D to VR styled games.